<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xsl-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>

<?xml-model href="../transforms/schemas/CCProtectionProfile.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="Mobile Device Fundamentals"
  xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <PPReference title="PP Reference" id="XXXXX">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Biometric cPP</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>3.1</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2017-06-16</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>3.1 Release 5</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>??</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>

  <RevisionHistory role="final">
    <entry>
      <version>0.1</version>
      <date>2016-06-24</date>
      <subject>Initial Version</subject>
    </entry>


  </RevisionHistory>


  <chapter id="int" title="Introduction">
    <section title="Objectives of Document" id="objdoc" toe-type="BIO"> This document comprises the
      Security Problem Definition for the biometric iTC. The iTC currently discusses three different
      TOE that are all covered by the content in this document, namely: <htm:ul>
        <htm:li>A TOE for presentation attack detection (PAD) only (also referred to as TOE.PAD), </htm:li>
        <htm:li>A TOE for biometric verification only (also referred to TOE.BIO),</htm:li>
        <htm:li>An integrated solution with PAD and biometric verification (also referred to as
          TOE.INT). </htm:li>
      </htm:ul> This document contains the description for TOE.BIO. The Security Problem Definition
      comprises: <htm:ul>
        <htm:li>A description of the external parties that interact with the TOE,</htm:li>
        <htm:li>A description of the assets to be protected by the TOE,</htm:li>
        <htm:li>A list of assumptions describing the intended environment of the TOE,</htm:li>
        <htm:li>A list of threats posed against the TOE,</htm:li>
        <htm:li>Organizational Security Policy (OSP) which is a set of rules, practices, and
          procedures imposed by an organization to address its security needs..</htm:li>
      </htm:ul> The Security Problem Definition defines the minimum set that applies to all possible
      architectures of the TOE. However, certain architectures of the TOE may face additional
      threats or OSPs and will also have to implement additional functionality. As an example: A
      biometric algorithm may generate suitable audit events to be recorded by its environment but
      has ‑ by itself ‑ no mean to record or handle the events. A complete biometric system on the
      other hand, has the functionality to store and handle audit events. This Protection Profile
      chooses the following approach to address this situation: <htm:ul>
        <htm:li>The requirements defined within the Security Problem Definition (and later on within
          the Objectives/SFR chapter) are to be met by every TOE, regardless of its
          architecture.)</htm:li>
        <htm:li>Chapter TBD defines additional functional packages that define additional
          requirements for certain architectures of a TOE.</htm:li>
        <htm:li>If a TOE meets the architecture of a functional package, the ST author shall include
          all requirements from that functional package to their ST. </htm:li> </htm:ul>
    </section>
    <section title="Scope of Document" id="scope"> The scope of the Protection Profile within the
      development and evaluation process is described in the Common Criteria for Information
      Technology Security Evaluation <cite linkend="CC"/>. In particular, a <abbr linkend="PP"/>
      defines the IT security requirements of a generic type of <abbr linkend="TOE"/> and specifies
      the functional and assurance security measures to be offered by that <abbr linkend="TOE"/> to
      meet stated requirements <cite linkend="CC"/>. </section>
    <section title="Intended Readership" id="intread"> The target audiences of this <abbr
        linkend="PP"/> are biometric Device developers, <abbr linkend="CC"/> consumers, evaluators and
      schemes. </section>
    <section title="Glossary" id="glos">
      <glossary>
        <entry>
          <term>PAD</term>
          <description>Presentation Attack Detection.</description>
        </entry>

      </glossary>
    </section>

    <section title="External Parties" id="parties" toe-type="BIO"> 

The following list comprises the external parties that may interact with the TOE.

<htm:dl>
        <htm:dt>Administrator </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>The TOE administrator is authorized and responsible to perform administrative TOE operations and able to use the administrative functions of the TOE. The administrator is also responsible for the installation and maintenance of the TOE. Depending on the concrete implementation of the TOE there may be more than one administrator and consequently also more than one administrative role. It is also possible that the role of the administrator is held by a user of the TOE. </htm:dd>        <htm:dt>User </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>A person who uses a biometric system to get enrolled or verified. </htm:dd>        <htm:dt>Attacker </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>An attacker is any individual who is attempting to subvert the operation of the TOE. </htm:dd>
      </htm:dl> 


     </section>    <section title="Assets" id="assets" toe-type="BIO"> 

The following table comprises the assets that are to be protected by the TOE


<htm:dl>
        <htm:dt>Access </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>A biometric authentication system is used to control access to a physical or logical portal. The access to this portal (or the decision about granting access to be precise) is a primary asset for every biometric authentication </htm:dd>        <htm:dt>PAD result </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>If the TOE implements a PAD system, the decision on whether an attempt with the TOE is considered being a Presentation Attack is a primary asset. </htm:dd>        <htm:dt>TSF Data </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>All data for the operation of the TOE upon which the enforcement of the security mechanisms relies. </htm:dd>
      </htm:dl> 


     </section>

<!-- Todo: This will have to be split up into the different TOE -->



    <section title="TOE Overview" id="toeov"> tbd
    </section>


    <section title="TOE Usage" id="toeus"> tbd </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter id="ccconf" title="CC Conformance"> As defined by the references <cite linkend="CC"/>,
    this <abbr linkend="PP"/> conforms to the requirements of Common Criteria v3.1, Revision 5. The
    methodology applied for the <abbr linkend="PP"/> evaluation is defined in <cite linkend="CEM"/>.
    <htm:br/><htm:br/> This <abbr linkend="PP"/> satisfies the following Assurance Families:
   tbd </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Problem Definition" id="spd">
    <section title="Threats" id="thr"> The following table comprises the threats that are directed against the TOE.
 <threats>
        <threat id="T.Casual_Attack" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>
            An attacker may attempt to impersonated as a legitimate user without being enrolled in the system themselves. In order to perform the attack, the attacker only uses their own biometric characteristic (in form of a zero-effort-attack) </description>

<!-- TBD: The objectives referrer will need to be added as soon as the objectives are there -->
        </threat>


        <threat id="T.PA_Enrolment" toe-type="PAD INT">
          <description> An attacker may attempt to get impersonated as another user during enrolment. In order to perform the attack, the attacker uses artificial biometric characteristics, carrying the biometric characteristic of the attacked user (as so called Presentation Attack) </description>
        </threat>


        <threat id="T.PA_Verification" toe-type="BIO">
          <description>An attacker may attempt to get impersonated (during verification process) as a legitimate user without being enrolled in the system themselves. In order to perform the attack, the attacker uses artificial biometric characteristics, carrying the biometric characteristic of the attacked user (as so called Presentation Attack) </description>
        </threat>

        <threat id="T.General" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>An attacker can carry out any kind of logical or physical attacks that do not exceed the attack potential and that are compliant with A.Environment as defined in the cPP in order to disguise his/her own identity during the enrolment or verification process or for the sake of impersonation.  More specifically, an attacker may try to modify TSF data (e.g. settings for the biometric verification process) in order to impact the normal operation of the TOE.</description>
        </threat>       


         <threat id="T.Residual" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>An attacker may try to take advantage of unprotected residual security relevant data (e.g. biometric data and settings) during a user's session or from a previous, already authenticated user.
In this way the attacker tries to get access to the security relevant settings of the TOE.
This threat covers several scenarios including:
- An attacker takes advantage of the verification memory content (e.g. by reading the memory content, cache or relevant temporary data) using a flaw in a user visible interface of the TOE.
- An attacker may take advantage of residual images at the capture device. These are likely to be limited to cases where physical contact with the biometric capture device is necessary for the biometric modality (e.g. fingerprints)</description>
        </threat>

         <threat id="T.Roles" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>An enrolled and authenticated user may try to exceed their privileges. This specifically addresses the cases where an authorized user tries to get administrator privileges in order to modify TSF data.</description>
        </threat>

      </threats>
    </section>





    <section title="Assumptions" id="assp"> The specific conditions listed below are assumed to
      exist in the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>’s Operational Environment. These include both practical
      realities in the development of the <abbr linkend="TOE"/> security requirements and the
      essential environmental conditions on the use of the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>. <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.CONFIG">
          <description>It is assumed that the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>’s security functions are
            configured correctly in a manner to ensure that the <abbr linkend="TOE"/> security
            policies will be enforced on all applicable network traffic flowing among the attached
            networks.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.CONFIG">
            <rationale>The operational environment objective OE.CONFIG is realized through A.CONFIG.
            </rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
      <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.NOTIFY">
          <description>It is assumed that the mobile user will immediately notify the administrator
            if the Mobile Device is lost or stolen.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.NOTIFY">
            <rationale>The operational environment objective OE.NOTIFY is realized through A.NOTIFY.
            </rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
      <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.PRECAUTION">
          <description>It is assumed that the mobile user exercises precautions to reduce the risk
            of loss or theft of the Mobile Device.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.PRECAUTION">
            <rationale>The operational environment objective OE.PRECAUTION is realized through
              A.PRECAUTION. </rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </section>


    <section title="Organizational Security Policies" id="osp"> The following list comprises the OSP that the TOE shall comply with.

      <OSPs>
        <OSP id="OSP.ENROL" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall implement the functionality to enrol users. The TOE shall ensure that enrolment records are of sufficient quality in order to meet the requirements on recognition performance. Start of Enrolment shall only be possible after authorization of an authorized administrator.</description>
<!--           <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGEMENT">
            <rationale>The organizational security policy P.ENTERPRISE is enforced through the
              objective O.MANAGEMENT as this objective represents how the enterprise and user assert
              management over the <abbr linkend="OS"/>.</rationale>
          </objective-refer> -->
        </OSP>

    <OSP id="OSP.Verifcation_Error" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall meet relevant criteria for its security relevant error rates for biometric verification (e.g. False Accept Rate (FAR) and False Rejection Rate (FRR)).</description>

        </OSP>



    <OSP id="OSP.PAD_Error" toe-type="PAD INT">
          <description>The TOE shall meet relevant criteria for its security relevant error rates for PAD.</description>

        </OSP>



    <OSP id="OSP.TrialLimit" toe-type="PAD BIO INT">
          <description>Impostors must be prevented from gaining access to the portal by making repeated verification attempts using one or more claimed user IDs.
Therefore the TOE in cooperation with its environment shall be able to limit the maximum number of unsuccessful verification attempts. </description>

        </OSP>


          <OSP id="OSP.Audit" toe-type="PAD BIO INT">
          <description>In order to <htm:ul>
          <htm:li>generate statistics that can be used to adjust the parameters for better quality (maintenance) </htm:li> 
           <htm:li>trace modification and</htm:li>
            <htm:li>trace possible attacks </htm:li> </htm:ul> the TOE shall generate security-relevant audit events. 
          </description>
            

        </OSP>


          <OSP id="OSP.Residual" toe-type="PAD BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall erase all residual security-relevant data once they are redundant.. This specifically includes (but is not limited to) all information left after enrolment, verification or PAD processing.
          </description>
            


        </OSP>

      </OSPs>



 </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="sobj">
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="sot"> The security objectives for the
      Mobile Device are defined as follows. <SOs>
        <SO id="O.COMMS">
          <description><htm:b>Protected Communications</htm:b><htm:br/><htm:br/> To address the
            network eavesdropping (T.EAVESDROP) and network attack (T.NETWORK) threats described in
              <secref linkend="thr"/>, concerning wireless transmission of Enterprise and user data
            and configuration data between the <abbr linkend="TOE"/> and remote network entities,
            conformant <abbr linkend="TOE"/>s will use a trusted communication path. The <abbr
              linkend="TOE"/> will be capable of communicating using one (or more) of these standard
            protocols: IPsec, DTLS, TLS, HTTPS, or Bluetooth. The protocols are specified by RFCs
            that offer a variety of implementation choices. Requirements have been imposed on some
            of these choices (particularly those for cryptographic primitives) to provide
            interoperability and resistance to cryptographic attack. <htm:br/><htm:br/> While
            conformant <abbr linkend="TOE"/>s must support all of the choices specified in the <abbr
              linkend="ST"/> including any optional <abbr linkend="SFR"/>s defined in this <abbr
              linkend="PP"/>, they may support additional algorithms and protocols. If such
            additional mechanisms are not evaluated, guidance must be given to the administrator to
            make clear the fact that they were not evaluated. </description>
<!--           <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.2(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.2(2)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.8"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(2)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(3)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(4)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(5)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_DTLS_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_HTTPS_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_SRV_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_SRV_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_TLSC_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_TLSC_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_TLSC_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_BLT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_IFC_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_STG_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_UPC_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.5"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.6"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.5"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_BLT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FTP_BLT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FTP_BLT_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FTP_ITC_EXT.1"/> -->
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.STORAGE">
          <description><htm:b>Protected Storage</htm:b><htm:br/><htm:br/> To address the issue of
            loss of confidentiality of user data in the event of loss of a Mobile Device
            (T.PHYSICAL), conformant <abbr linkend="TOE"/>s will use data-at-rest protection. The
              <abbr linkend="TOE"/> will be capable of encrypting data and keys stored on the device
            and will prevent unauthorized access to encrypted data. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.5"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.6"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.7"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(2)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(3)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(4)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(5)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_IV_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_STG_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_STG_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_STG_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_ACF_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_ACF_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_DAR_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_DAR_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_UAU_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_KST_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_KST_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_KST_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_JTA_EXT.1"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.CONFIG">
          <description><htm:b>Mobile Device Configuration</htm:b><htm:br/><htm:br/> To ensure a
            Mobile Device protects user and enterprise data that it may store or process, conformant
              <abbr linkend="TOE"/>s will provide the capability to configure and apply security
            policies defined by the user and the Enterprise Administrator. If Enterprise security
            policies are configured these must be applied in precedence of user specified security
            policies. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FMT_MOF_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FMT_SMF_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FMT_SMF_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FTA_TAB.1"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.AUTH">
          <description><htm:b>Authorization and Authentication</htm:b><htm:br/><htm:br/> To address
            the issue of loss of confidentiality of user data in the event of loss of a Mobile
            Device (T.PHYSICAL), users are required to enter an authentication factor to the device
            prior to accessing protected functionality and data. Some non-sensitive functionality
            (e.g., emergency calling, text notification) can be accessed prior to entering the
            authentication factor. The device will automatically lock following a configured period
            of inactivity in an attempt to ensure authorization will be required in the event of the
            device being lost or stolen.<htm:br/><htm:br/> Authentication of the endpoints of a
            trusted communication path is required for network access to ensure attacks are unable
            to establish unauthorized network connections to undermine the integrity of the device.
            <htm:br/><htm:br/> Repeated attempts by a user to authorize to the <abbr linkend="TSF"/>
            will be limited or throttled to enforce a delay between unsuccessful attempts.<htm:br/>
          </description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.2(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PBA_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_AFL_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BMG_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BMG_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BMG_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BMG_EXT.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BMG_EXT.5"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_BMG_EXT.6"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_PMG_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_TRT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_UAU_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_UAU_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_UAU_EXT.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_UAU.5"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_UAU.6"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_UAU.7"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.5"/>
          <component-refer ref="FTA_SSL_EXT.1"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.INTEGRITY">
          <description><htm:b>Mobile Device Integrity</htm:b><htm:br/><htm:br/> To ensure the
            integrity of the Mobile Device is maintained conformant <abbr linkend="TOE"/>s will
            perform self-tests to ensure the integrity of critical functionality, software/firmware
            and data has been maintained. The user shall be notified of any failure of these
            self-tests. This will protect against the threat T.PERSISTENT. <htm:br/><htm:br/> To
            address the issue of an application containing malicious or flawed code (T.FLAWAPP), the
            integrity of downloaded updates to software/firmware will be verified prior to
            installation/execution of the object on the Mobile Device. In addition, the <abbr
              linkend="TOE"/> will restrict applications to only have access to the system services
            and data they are permitted to interact with. The <abbr linkend="TOE"/> will further
            protect against malicious applications from gaining access to data they are not
            authorized to access by randomizing the memory layout. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FAU_GEN.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FAU_SAR.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FAU_SEL.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FAU_STG.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FAU_STG.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(2)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(3)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_ACF_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_ACF_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_AEX_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_AEX_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_AEX_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_AEX_EXT.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_AEX_EXT.5"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_AEX_EXT.6"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_AEX_EXT.7"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_BBD_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_NOT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_NOT_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_STM.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TST_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TST_EXT.2(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TST_EXT.2(2)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TST_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TUD_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TUD_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TUD_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_TUD_EXT.4"/>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PRIVACY">
          <description><htm:b>End User Privacy and Device Functionality</htm:b><htm:br/><htm:br/> In
            a BYOD environment (use cases 3 and 4), a personally-owned mobile device is used for
            both personal activities and enterprise data. Enterprise management solutions may have
            the technical capability to monitor and enforce security policies on the device.
            However, the privacy of the personal activities and data must be ensured. In addition,
            since there are limited controls that the enterprise can enforce on the personal side,
            separation of personal and enterprise data is needed. This will protect against the
            T.FLAWAPP and T.PERSISTENT threats. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_ACF_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_BCK_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FMT_SMF_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FMT_SMF_EXT.3"/>
        </SO>
      </SOs>
    </section>
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment" id="sooe"> The following
      security objectives for the operational environment assist the <abbr linkend="OS"/> in
      correctly providing its security functionality. These track with the assumptions about the
      environment. <SOEs>
        <SOE id="OE.CONFIG">
          <description>TOE administrators will configure the Mobile Device security functions
            correctly to create the intended security policy</description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.NOTIFY">
          <description>The Mobile User will immediately notify the administrator if the Mobile
            Device is lost or stolen.</description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.PRECAUTION">
          <description>The Mobile User exercises precautions to reduce the risk of loss or theft of
            the Mobile Device.</description>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs>
    </section>
    <section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="SOR">This section describes how the
      assumptions, threats, and organizational security policies map to the security objectives.
      <InsertSPDCorrespondence/></section>
  </chapter>

  <appendix id="biblio" title="References">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="CC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - <htm:ul>
            <htm:li><htm:a
                href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part 1:
                Introduction and General Model</htm:a>, CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</htm:li>
            <htm:li><htm:a
                href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part 2:
                Security Functional Components</htm:a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</htm:li>
            <htm:li><htm:a
                href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part 3:
                Security Assurance Components</htm:a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</htm:li>
          </htm:ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="CEM">
        <tag>CEM</tag>
        <description>
          <htm:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CEMV3.1R4.pdf">Common
            Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security - Evaluation
            Methodology</htm:a>, CCMB-2012-09-004, Version 3.1, Revision 4, September 2012.
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="NFIQ1.0">
        <tag>NFIQ 1.0</tag>
        <description>
          <htm:a
            href="http://biometrics.nist.gov/cs_links/standard/archived/workshops/workshop1/presentations/Tabassi-Image-Quality.pdf"
            >NIST Fingerprint Image Quality and relation to PIV</htm:a>, Tabassi, Elham.NIST
          Information Technology Laboratory, 2005. Retrieved June 13, 2015. </description>
      </entry>

      <entry id="NFIQ2.0">
        <tag>NFIQ 2.0</tag>
        <description>
          <htm:a
            href="http://biometrics.nist.gov/cs_links/ibpc2016/presentations/ibpc2016_may04/13_tabassi_ibpc2016_nfiq_4May2016.pdf"
            >Biometric Quality: The push towards zero error biometrics.</htm:a>, Tabassi, Elham et
          al. International Biometrics Performance Conference (IBPC), 2016. Retrieved May 30, 2016.
        </description>
      </entry>

      <entry id="IBPC">
        <tag>IBPC</tag>
        <description>
          <htm:a
            href="http://biometrics.nist.gov/cs_links/ibpc2010/pdfs/Henniger_Olaf_IBPC-Presentation.pdf"
            >On security evaluation of fingerprint recognition systems-- IBPC Presentation.</htm:a>,
          Henniger, Scheuermann, and Kniess.International Biometric Performance Testing Conference
          (IBPC), 2010. Retrieved June 12, 2015. </description>
      </entry>

      <entry id="ISO19989">
        <tag>ISO 19989</tag>
        <description>
          <htm:a
            href="http://www.iso.org/iso/home/store/catalogue_tc/catalogue_detail.htm?csnumber=66801"
            >, ISO/IEC NP 19989: Evaluation of presentation attack detection for biometrics</htm:a>
          International Organization for Standardization (ISO), 2014. </description>
      </entry>

      <entry id="ANSI409.1">
        <tag>ANSI 409.1</tag>
        <description> ANSI/CITS 409.1-2005. Biometrics Performance Testing and Reporting—Part 1:
          Principles and Findings.” Annex B. ANSI/CITS, 2005. </description>
      </entry>

      <entry id="NIST">
        <tag>NIST</tag>
        <description>
          <htm:a
            href="http://www.isca-speech.org/archive_open/archive_papers/odyssey/pres/odys_doddington_p.pdf"
            >The NIST speaker recognition evaluation—Overview, methodology, systems, results,
            perspective</htm:a>, Doddington, Przybocki, Martin, and Reynolds. Speech Communication
          31: Elsevier, 2000, Retrieved June 10, 2015. </description>
      </entry>

      <entry id="Brown">
        <tag>BROWN</tag>
        <description>
          <htm:a href="http://projecteuclid.org/download/pdf_1/euclid.ss/1009213286">Interval
            Estimation for a Binomial Proportion.</htm:a>Brown, Cai, and DasGupta. </description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>
  <appendix id="ack" title="Acknowledgements"> This protection profile was developed by the Mobility
    Technical Community with representatives from industry, U.S. Government agencies, Common
    Criteria Test Laboratories, and international Common Criteria schemes. The National Information
    Assurance Partnership wishes to acknowledge and thank the members of this group whose dedicated
    efforts contributed significantly to the publication. These organizations include: <htm:br/><htm:br/>
    <htm:b>U.S. Government</htm:b><htm:br/> Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA)<htm:br/>
    Information Assurance Directorate (IAD)<htm:br/> National Information Assurance Partnership
    (NIAP)<htm:br/> National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)<htm:br/><htm:br/>
    <htm:b>International Common Criteria Schemes</htm:b><htm:br/> Australasian Information Security
    Evaluation Program (AISEP)<htm:br/> Canadian Common Criteria Evaluation and Certification Scheme
    (CSEC)<htm:br/> Information-technology Promotion Agency, Japan (IPA)<htm:br/> UK IT Security
    Evaluation and Certificate Scheme (NCSC)<htm:br/><htm:br/>
    <htm:b>Industry</htm:b><htm:br/> Apple, Inc.<htm:br/> BlackBerry<htm:br/> LG Electronics,
    Inc.<htm:br/> Microsoft Corporation<htm:br/> Motorola Solutions<htm:br/> Samsung Electronics
    Co., Ltd.<htm:br/> Other Members of the Mobility Technical Community<htm:br/><htm:br/>
    <htm:b>Common Criteria Test Laboratories</htm:b><htm:br/> EWA-Canada, Ltd.<htm:br/> Gossamer
    Security Solutions<htm:br/>
  </appendix>

  <extra-css>
    <!--  .LsVerySpecificUseCase::before { content: "Note["; }
  .LsVerySpecificUseCase { text-decoration: line-through;}
  .LsVerySpecificUseCase::after { content: "]"; }-->
    <!-- <htm:div class="LsVerySpecificUseCase">--> .SOlist .optional::after, .SOlist
    .sel-based::after, .SOlist .objective::after { content: "(OPTIONAL)" } </extra-css>
</PP>
