<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xsl-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>
<?xml-model href="../transforms/schemas/CCProtectionProfile.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<PP name="Mobile Device Fundamentals" xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <PPReference id="XXXXX" title="PP Reference">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Biometric cPP</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>3.1</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>tbd</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2017-07-01</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>3.1 Release 5</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>??</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>tbd</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory role="draft">
    <entry>
      <version>0.1</version>
      <date>2016-06-24</date>
      <subject>Initial Version</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <chapter id="int" title="Introduction">
    <section id="objdoc" title="Objectives of Document" toe-type="BIO">This document comprises the
      Security Problem Definition for the biometric iTC. The iTC currently discusses three different
      TOE that are all covered by the content in this document, namely: 
      
      
      <htm:ul>
        <htm:li>A TOE for presentation attack detection (PAD) only (also referred to as TOE.PAD), </htm:li>
        <htm:li>A TOE for biometric verification only (also referred to TOE.BIO),</htm:li>
        <htm:li>An integrated solution with PAD and biometric verification (also referred to as
          TOE.INT). </htm:li></htm:ul>This document contains the description for TOE.BIO. The
      Security Problem Definition comprises: 
      
      
      <htm:ul>
        <htm:li>A description of the external parties that interact with the TOE,</htm:li>
        <htm:li>A description of the assets to be protected by the TOE,</htm:li>
        <htm:li>A list of assumptions describing the intended environment of the TOE,</htm:li>
        <htm:li>A list of threats posed against the TOE,</htm:li>
        <htm:li>Organizational Security Policy (OSP) which is a set of rules, practices, and
          procedures imposed by an organization to address its security needs..</htm:li></htm:ul>The
      Security Problem Definition defines the minimum set that applies to all possible architectures
      of the TOE. However, certain architectures of the TOE may face additional threats or OSPs and
      will also have to implement additional functionality. As an example: A biometric algorithm may
      generate suitable audit events to be recorded by its environment but has ‑ by itself ‑ no mean
      to record or handle the events. A complete biometric system on the other hand, has the
      functionality to store and handle audit events. This Protection Profile chooses the following
      approach to address this situation: 
      
      
      <htm:ul>
        <htm:li>The requirements defined within the Security Problem Definition (and later on within
          the Objectives/SFR chapter) are to be met by every TOE, regardless of its
          architecture.)</htm:li>
        <htm:li>Chapter TBD defines additional functional packages that define additional
          requirements for certain architectures of a TOE.</htm:li>
        <htm:li>If a TOE meets the architecture of a functional package, the ST author shall include
          all requirements from that functional package to their ST. </htm:li></htm:ul>
    </section>
    <!-- *****************************
  ____                       
 / ___|  ___ ___  _ __   ___ 
 \___ \ / __/ _ \| '_ \ / _ \
  ___) | (_| (_) | |_) |  __/
 |____/ \___\___/| .__/ \___|
                 |_|         
*****************************
 -->
    <section id="scope" title="Scope of Document">The scope of the Protection Profile within the
      development and evaluation process is described in the Common Criteria for Information
      Technology Security Evaluation 
      
      
      <cite linkend="CC"/>
      . In particular, a 
      
      
      <abbr linkend="PP"/>
      defines the IT security requirements of a generic type of 
      
      
      <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
      and specifies
      the functional and assurance security measures to be offered by that 
      
      
      <abbr linkend="TOE"/>
      to
      meet stated requirements 
      
      
      <cite linkend="CC"/>
      . </section>
    <section id="intread" title="Intended Readership">The target audiences of this 
      
      
      <abbr linkend="PP"/>
      are biometric Device developers, 
      
      
      <abbr linkend="CC"/>
      consumers, evaluators
      and schemes. </section>
    <section id="glos" title="Glossary">
      <glossary>
        <entry>
          <term>PAD</term>
          <description>Presentation Attack Detection.</description>
        </entry>
      </glossary>
    </section>
    <!-- **********************************************************************
  _____      _                        _   ____            _   _           
 | ____|_  _| |_ ___ _ __ _ __   __ _| | |  _ \ __ _ _ __| |_(_) ___  ___ 
 |  _| \ \/ / __/ _ \ '__| '_ \ / _` | | | |_) / _` | '__| __| |/ _ \/ __|
 | |___ ><| ||  __/ |  | | | | (_| | | |  __/ (_| | |  | |_| |  __/\__ \
 |_____/_/\_\\__\___|_|  |_| |_|\__,_|_| |_|   \__,_|_|   \__|_|\___||___/
                                                                          
***************************************************************************
 -->
    <section id="parties" title="External Parties" toe-type="BIO">The following list comprises the
      external parties that may interact with the TOE. 
      
      
      <htm:dl>
        <htm:dt>Administrator </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>The TOE administrator is authorized and responsible to perform administrative TOE
          operations and able to use the administrative functions of the TOE. The administrator is
          also responsible for the installation and maintenance of the TOE. Depending on the
          concrete implementation of the TOE there may be more than one administrator and
          consequently also more than one administrative role. It is also possible that the role of
          the administrator is held by a user of the TOE. </htm:dd>
        <htm:dt>User </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>A person who uses a biometric system to get enrolled or verified. </htm:dd>
        <htm:dt>Attacker </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>An attacker is any individual who is attempting to subvert the operation of the TOE.</htm:dd></htm:dl>
    </section>
    <!-- ********************************
    / \   ___ ___  ___| |_ ___ 
   / _ \ / __/ __|/ _ \ __/ __|
  / ___ \\__ \__ \  __/ |_\__ \
 /_/   \_\___/___/\___|\__|___/
******************************** -->
    <section id="assets" title="Assets" toe-type="BIO">The following table comprises the assets that
      are to be protected by the TOE 
      
      
      <htm:dl>
        <htm:dt>Access </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>A biometric authentication system is used to control access to a physical or logical
          portal. The access to this portal (or the decision about granting access to be precise) is
          a primary asset for every biometric authentication </htm:dd>
        <htm:dt>PAD result </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>If the TOE implements a PAD system, the decision on whether an attempt with the TOE
          is considered being a Presentation Attack is a primary asset. </htm:dd>
        <htm:dt>TSF Data </htm:dt>
        <htm:dd>All data for the operation of the TOE upon which the enforcement of the security
          mechanisms relies. </htm:dd></htm:dl>
    </section>
    <!-- ****************************************************************
 |_   _/ _ \| ____|  / _ \__   _____ _ ____   _(_) _____      __
   | || | | |  _|   | | | \ \ / / _ \ '__\ \ / / |/ _ \ \ /\ / /
   | || |_| | |___  | |_| |\ V /  __/ |   \ V /| |  __/\ V  V / 
   |_| \___/|_____|  \___/  \_/ \___|_|    \_/ |_|\___| \_/\_/ 
**************************************************************** -->
    <!-- Todo: This will have to be split up into the different TOE -->
    <section id="toeov" title="TOE Overview">tbd </section>
    <!-- ************************************************
 |_   _/ _ \| ____| | | | |___  __ _  __ _  ___ 
   | || | | |  _|   | | | / __|/ _` |/ _` |/ _ \
   | || |_| | |___  | |_| \__ \ (_| | (_| |  __/
   |_| \___/|_____|  \___/|___/\__,_|\__, |\___|
                                     |___/      
************************************************ -->
    <section id="toeus" title="TOE Usage">tbd </section>
  </chapter>
  <!-- ************************************************************************************************
   ____             __                                              ____ _       _               
  / ___|___  _ __  / _| ___  _ __ _ __ ___   __ _ _ __   ___ ___   / ___| | __ _(_)_ __ ___  ___ 
 | |   / _ \| '_ \| |_ / _ \| '__| '_ ` _ \ / _` | '_ \ / __/ _ \ | |   | |/ _` | | '_ ` _ \/ __|
 | |__| (_) | | | |  _| (_) | |  | | | | | | (_| | | | | (_|  __/ | |___| | (_| | | | | | | \__ \
  \____\___/|_| |_|_|  \___/|_|  |_| |_| |_|\__,_|_| |_|\___\___|  \____|_|\__,_|_|_| |_| |_|___/
************************************************************************************************ -->
  <chapter id="ccconf" title="CC Conformance">As defined by the references  
    <cite linkend="CC"/>
    , this  
    <abbr linkend="PP"/>
    conforms to the requirements of Common Criteria v3.1, Revision 5. The methodology applied for the  
    <abbr linkend="PP"/>
    evaluation is defined in 
    <cite linkend="CEM"/>
    . 
    
    <htm:br/>
    <htm:br/>
    This 
    <abbr linkend="PP"/>
    satisfies the following Assurance Families: tbd </chapter>
  <chapter id="spd" title="Security Problem Definition">
    <!-- **************************************
  _____ _                    _       
 |_   _| |__  _ __ ___  __ _| |_ ___ 
   | | | '_ \| '__/ _ \/ _` | __/ __|
   | | | | | | | |  __/ (_| | |_\__ \
   |_| |_| |_|_|  \___|\__,_|\__|___/
                                    
************************************** -->
    <section id="thr" title="Threats">The following table comprises the threats that are directed
      against the TOE. 
      
      
      <threats>
        <threat id="T.Casual_Attack" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>An attacker may attempt to impersonated as a legitimate user without being
            enrolled in the system themselves. In order to perform the attack, the attacker only
            uses their own biometric characteristic (in form of a zero-effort-attack) </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.BIO_VERIFICATION">
            <rationale>The threat T.EAVESDROP is countered by O.BIO_VERIFICATION as this objective requires the TOE to provide a biometric authentication mechanism that is resistant against attacks of this kind.</rationale></objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.PA_Enrolment" toe-type="PAD INT">
          <description>An attacker may attempt to get impersonated as another user during enrolment.
            In order to perform the attack, the attacker uses artificial biometric characteristics,
            carrying the biometric characteristic of the attacked user (as so called Presentation
            Attack) </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PAD">
            <rationale>Tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PAD_ENROL">
            <rationale>Tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.ENROL">
            <rationale>tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.PA_Verification" toe-type="BIO">
          <description>An attacker may attempt to get impersonated (during verification process) as
            a legitimate user without being enrolled in the system themselves. In order to perform
            the attack, the attacker uses artificial biometric characteristics, carrying the
            biometric characteristic of the attacked user (as so called Presentation Attack)
          </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.BIO_VERIFICATION">
            <rationale>tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PAD">
            <rationale>tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PAD_VERIFICATION">
            <rationale>tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.General" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>An attacker can carry out any kind of logical or physical attacks that do not
            exceed the attack potential and that are compliant with A.Environment as defined in the
            cPP in order to disguise his/her own identity during the enrolment or verification
            process or for the sake of impersonation. More specifically, an attacker may try to
            modify TSF data (e.g. settings for the biometric verification process) in order to
            impact the normal operation of the TOE.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTION">
            <rationale>tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.Residual" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>An attacker may try to take advantage of unprotected residual security
            relevant data (e.g. biometric data and settings) during a user's session or from a
            previous, already authenticated user. In this way the attacker tries to get access to
            the security relevant settings of the TOE. This threat covers several scenarios
            including: - An attacker takes advantage of the verification memory content (e.g. by
            reading the memory content, cache or relevant temporary data) using a flaw in a user
            visible interface of the TOE. - An attacker may take advantage of residual images at the
            capture device. These are likely to be limited to cases where physical contact with the
            biometric capture device is necessary for the biometric modality (e.g.
            fingerprints)</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.RESIDUAL">
            <rationale>tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.Roles" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>An enrolled and authenticated user may try to exceed their privileges. This
            specifically addresses the cases where an authorized user tries to get administrator
            privileges in order to modify TSF data.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGEMENT">
            <rationale>tbd</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
      </threats>
    </section>*
    <!-- **********************************************************
   __ _ ___ ___ _   _ _ __ ___  _ __ | |_(_) ___  _ __  ___ 
  / _` / __/ __| | | | '_ ` _ \| '_ \| __| |/ _ \| '_ \/ __|
 | (_| \__ \__ \ |_| | | | | | | |_) | |_| | (_) | | | \__ \
  \__,_|___/___/\__,_|_| |_| |_| .__/ \__|_|\___/|_| |_|___/
                               |_|                        
***********************************************************
 -->
    <section id="assp" title="Assumptions">
      The following table comprises the assets that assumptions
      about the intended environment of the TOE. 
      
      
      <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.Admin" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>It is assumed that the administrator of the TOE is well trained and
            non-hostile. Non-hostile specifically means that the administrator does not become an
            attacker nor does the administrator give relevant information to attackers. The
            administrator is responsible to accompany the TOE installation and oversees the system
            requirements regarding the TOE as well as the TOE settings and requirements. </description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.Admin">
            <rationale>The assumption A.Admin is covered by the security objective OE.Admin. The assumption and the objective are drafted in a way that the correspondence is obvious.</rationale></objective-refer>
        </assumption>
        <assumption id="A.Environment" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The TOE is assumed to be used in a semi-controlled and observable environment
            (i.e. attacks that require extensive time or extensive access to the TOE or the use of
            complex tools (in the sense of conspicuous tools) are considered impractical during
            exploitation phase). This assumption also includes the protection of any parameters used
            by the TOE. </description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.Environment">
            <rationale>The assumption A.Environment is covered by the security objective OE.Environment. The assumption and the objective are drafted in a way that the correspondence is obvious.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
        <assumption id="A.Comm" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>It is assumed that the communication between the components of the biometric
            product is adequately protected against manipulation and eavesdropping of information.
          </description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.Comm">
            <rationale>The assumption A.Comm is covered by the security objective OE.Comm. The assumption and the objective are drafted in a way that the correspondence is obvious.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
        <assumption id="A.Fallback" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>It is assumed that a fall-back mechanism as a complement to the TOE is
            available that reaches at least the same level of security as the biometric verification
            system does. This fall-back system is used in cases where an authorized user is rejected
            by the biometric verification system (False Rejection). </description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.Fallback">
            <rationale>The assumption A.Fallback is covered by the security objective OE.Fallback. The assumption and the objective are drafted in a way that the correspondence is obvious.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
        <assumption id="A.Bio" toe-type="PAD">
          <description>The biometric system protected by the TOE ensures that all threats that are
            not related to presentation attacks are appropriately handled. Further, the biometric
            system ensures that the functionality of the TOE is invoked/used in order to protect the
            biometric system against presentation attacks. It is also assumed that the biometric
            sample that is acquired by the capture devices belongs to the sample that is used for
            presentation attack detection.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.Bio">
            <rationale>The assumption A.Bio is covered by the security objective OE.Bio. The assumption and the objective are drafted in a way that the correspondence is obvious.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <appnote>The PAD system addressed in this Protection Profile is a protection mechanism
            against presentation attacks. </appnote>
        </assumption>
        <assumption id="A.PAD" toe-type="BIO">
          <description>It is assumed that the biometric system is protected against Presentation
            Attacks according to PP [bioCPP].</description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.PAD">
            <rationale>The assumption A.PAD is covered by the security objective OE.PAD. The assumption and the objective are drafted in a way that the correspondence is obvious.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <note role="application">The PAD system addressed in this Protection Profile is a
            protection mechanism against presentation attacks. </note>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </section>
    <!-- *******************
  / _ \/ ___||  _ \ 
 | | | \___ \| |_) |
 | |_| |___) |  __/ 
  \___/|____/|_|    
 *******************   -->
    <section id="osp" title="Organizational Security Policies">The following list comprises the OSP
      that the TOE shall comply with. 
      
      
      <OSPs>
        <OSP id="OSP.ENROL" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall implement the functionality to enrol users. The TOE shall
            ensure that enrolment records are of sufficient quality in order to meet the
            requirements on recognition performance. Start of Enrolment shall only be possible after
            authorization of an authorized administrator.</description>
          <!--           <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGEMENT"><rationale>The organizational security policy P.ENTERPRISE is enforced through the
              objective O.MANAGEMENT as this objective represents how the enterprise and user assert
              management over the <abbr linkend="OS"/>.</rationale></objective-refer>--></OSP>
        <OSP id="OSP.Verifcation_Error" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall meet relevant criteria for its security relevant error rates
            for biometric verification (e.g. False Accept Rate (FAR) and False Rejection Rate
            (FRR)).</description>
        </OSP>
        <OSP id="OSP.PAD_Error" toe-type="PAD INT">
          <description>The TOE shall meet relevant criteria for its security relevant error rates
            for PAD.</description>
        </OSP>
        <OSP id="OSP.TrialLimit" toe-type="PAD BIO INT">
          <description>Impostors must be prevented from gaining access to the portal by making
            repeated verification attempts using one or more claimed user IDs. Therefore the TOE in
            cooperation with its environment shall be able to limit the maximum number of
            unsuccessful verification attempts. </description>
        </OSP>
        <OSP id="OSP.Audit" toe-type="PAD BIO INT">
          <description>In order to 
            
            
            <htm:ul>
              <htm:li>generate statistics that can be used to adjust the parameters for better
                quality (maintenance) </htm:li>
              <htm:li>trace modification and</htm:li>
              <htm:li>trace possible attacks </htm:li></htm:ul>the TOE shall generate
            security-relevant audit events. </description>
        </OSP>
        <OSP id="OSP.Residual" toe-type="PAD BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall erase all residual security-relevant data once they are
            redundant.. This specifically includes (but is not limited to) all information left
            after enrolment, verification or PAD processing. </description>
        </OSP>
      </OSPs>
    </section>
  </chapter>*
  <!-- ************************************************************************************
                           _ _                 _     _           _   _                
  ___  ___  ___ _   _ _ __(_) |_ _   _    ___ | |__ (_) ___  ___| |_(_)_   _____  ___ 
 / __|/ _ \/ __| | | | '__| | __| | | |  / _ \| '_ \| |/ _ \/ __| __| \ \ / / _ \/ __|
 \__ \  __/ (__| |_| | |  | | |_| |_| | | (_) | |_) | |  __/ (__| |_| |\ V /  __/\__ \
 |___/\___|\___|\__,_|_|  |_|\__|\__, |  \___/|_.__// |\___|\___|\__|_| \_/ \___||___/
                                 |___/            |__/                                
*************************************************************************************
 -->
  <chapter id="sobj" title="Security Objectives">
    <section id="sot" title="Security Objectives for the TOE">
      The security objectives for the Mobile
      Device are defined as follows. 
      
      
      <SOs>
        <SO id="O.BIO_VERIFICATION" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall provide a biometric verification mechanism to ensure access to
            a portal with an adequate reliability. The TOE shall meet relevant criteria for its
            security relevant error rates for biometric verification (e.g. False Accept Rate (FAR)
            and False Rejection Rate (FRR)). An “Exact match” should not be counted as a positive
            verification as it may be a replay attempt.</description>
          <!--           <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.1"/><component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.2(1)"/><component-refer ref="FCS_CKM.2(2)"/><component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.8"/><component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(1)"/><component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(2)"/><component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(3)"/><component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(4)"/><component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(5)"/><component-refer ref="FCS_DTLS_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FCS_HTTPS_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.2"/><component-refer ref="FCS_RBG_EXT.3"/><component-refer ref="FCS_SRV_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FCS_SRV_EXT.2"/><component-refer ref="FCS_TLSC_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FCS_TLSC_EXT.2"/><component-refer ref="FCS_TLSC_EXT.3"/><component-refer ref="FDP_BLT_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FDP_IFC_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FDP_STG_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FDP_UPC_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.2"/><component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.3"/><component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.4"/><component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.5"/><component-refer ref="FIA_BLT_EXT.6"/><component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.2"/><component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.3"/><component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.4"/><component-refer ref="FIA_X509_EXT.5"/><component-refer ref="FPT_BLT_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FTP_BLT_EXT.1"/><component-refer ref="FTP_BLT_EXT.2"/><component-refer ref="FTP_ITC_EXT.1"/>--></SO>
        <SO id="O.PAD" toe-type="PAD">
          <description>The TOE shall detect whether a presentation is an presentation attack is or a
            bona fide presentation. The evidence may be extracted from the data provided by the same
            sensor that is used to acquire the biometric characteristic for recognition (by the
            biometric system in the environment), or it may be retrieved using sensors which are
            solely dedicated to PAD. </description>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PAD" toe-type="PAD">
          <description>The TOE shall detect whether a presentation is an presentation attack is or a
            bona fide presentation. The evidence may be extracted from the data provided by the same
            sensor that is used to acquire the biometric characteristic for recognition (by the
            biometric system in the environment), or it may be retrieved using sensors which are
            solely dedicated to PAD. </description>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PAD_ENROL" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall prevent an attacker facilitating a presentation attack from
            being successfully enrolled, </description>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PAD_VERIFICATION" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE shall prevent an attacker facilitating a presentation attack from
            being successfully verified. </description>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.AUDIT" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The TOE shall report or record 
            <htm:ul>
              <li>A use of the central functionality of the TOE and its result</li>
              <li>Every use of a management function </li>
              <li>All parameters modified by the management functions</li></htm:ul>
          </description>
          <appnote>The use of the central functionality of the TOE refers to the use of the PAD
            functionality in case of TOE.PAD and to the use of the biometric functionality in case
            of TOE.BIO.</appnote>
          <appnote>Please note that the term “report” in O.Audit does only require the TOE to
            generate the audit event while it is possible that the storage of the events is done by
            the environment. </appnote>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.ENROL" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The TOE shall implement the functionality to enrol users. The TOE shall
            ensure that enrolment records are of sufficient quality in order to meet the
            requirements on recognition performance. The TOE shall ensure that start of Enrolment
            shall only be possible after authorization by an administrator. </description>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.RESIDUAL" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The TOE shall ensure that no residual or unprotected security relevant data
            remain in memory or on any sensor after operations are completed. </description>
          <appnote>In case no sensor is part of the TOE, this part of the objective shall be
            considered fulfilled. </appnote>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.MANAGEMENT" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The TOE shall provide the necessary management functionality for the
            modification of security relevant parameters to TOE administrators only. As part of this
            management functionality the TOE shall only accept secure values for security relevant
            parameters to ensure the correct operation of the TOE. </description>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PAD_ERROR" toe-type="PAD INT">
          <description>The TOE shall meet relevant criteria for its security relevant error rates
            for PAD </description>
          <appnote>It is the concept of this PP that concrete values for security relevant error
            rates shall not be defined in the PP/ST. Instead, such concrete values should be defined
            in the corresponding methodology documents. </appnote>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PROTECTION" toe-type="BIO INT">
          <description>The TOE in cooperation with its immediate environment shall provide an
            adequate level of logical and physical protection in order to ensure the correct
            operation of the TOE. This specifically concerns the enrolment and verification process.
            Impostors must be prevented from gaining access to the portal by making repeated
            verification attempts using one or more claimed user IDs. Therefore the TOE in
            cooperation with its environment shall be able to limit the maximum number of
            unsuccessful verification attempts. Also, the TOE ‑ in cooperation with its environment
            ‑ shall ensure that any TSF data is adequately protected. </description>
          <appnote>The relationship between the TOE and its environment is pretty complex in this
            point and deserves some further explanation: A.Environment does not pose an absolute
            protection for the TOE to be provided by the environment. It provides a level of
            protection, in which complex attacks may not be possible. However, simple and
            unobstrusive attacks can still be performed. Such attacks are described in T.General and
            have to be countered by the TOE itself as required by this objective. </appnote>
        </SO>
      </SOs>
      <!--******************************************************************************************
  ____                       _ _            ___  _     _           _   _                
 / ___|  ___  ___ _   _ _ __(_) |_ _   _   / _ \| |__ (_) ___  ___| |_(_)_   _____  ___ 
 \___ \ / _ \/ __| | | | '__| | __| | | | | | | | '_ \| |/ _ \/ __| __| \ \ / / _ \/ __|
  ___) |  __/ (__| |_| | |  | | |_| |_| | | |_| | |_) | |  __/ (__| |_| |\ V /  __/\__ \
 |____/ \___|\___|\__,_|_|  |_|\__|\__, |  \___/|_.__// |\___|\___|\__|_| \_/ \___||___/
                                   |___/            |__/                                
   __              _   _                            _                                      _   
  / _| ___  _ __  | |_| |__   ___    ___ _ ____   _(_)_ __ ___  _ __  _ __ ___   ___ _ __ | |_ 
 | |_ / _ \| '__| | __| '_ \ / _ \  / _ \ '_ \ \ / / | '__/ _ \| '_ \| '_ ` _ \ / _ \ '_ \| __|
 |  _| (_) | |    | |_| | | |  __/ |  __/ | | \ V /| | | | (_) | | | | | | | | |  __/ | | | |_ 
 |_|  \___/|_|     \__|_| |_|\___|  \___|_| |_|\_/ |_|_|  \___/|_| |_|_| |_| |_|\___|_| |_|\__|
 *************************************************************************************-->
    </section>
    <section id="sooe" title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment">The following
      security objectives for the operational environment assist the TOE in correctly providing its
      security functionality. These track with the assumptions about the environment. 
      
      
      <SOEs>
        <SOE id="OE.ADMIN" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The administrator of the TOE shall be well trained and non-hostile.
            Non-hostile specifically means that the administrator does not become an attacker nor
            does the administrator give relevant information to attackers. The administrator is
            responsible to witness the TOE installation and oversees the system requirements
            regarding the TOE. </description></SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.Environment" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The direct environment of the TOE shall be semi-controlled and observable.
            This specifically means that attacks that require extensive time or extensive access to
            the TOE or the use of complex tools (in the sense of conspicuous tools) shall be
            rendered impractical by the environment. </description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.COMM" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The direct environment of the TOE shall adequately protect the communication
            between the components of the biometric product against manipulation and eavesdropping
          </description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.FALLBACK" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The environment shall provide a fall-back mechanism as a complement to the
            TOE that reaches at least the same level of security as the biometric verification
            system. This fall-back system is used in cases where an authorized user is rejected by
            the biometric verification system (False Rejection). </description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.FALLBACK" toe-type="PAD">
          <description>The biometric system protected by the TOE shall ensure that all threats that
            are not related to PAD are appropriately handled. Further, the biometric system ensures
            that the functionality of the TOE is invoked/used in order to protect the biometric
            system against Presentation Attacks. It is also assumed that the biometric sample that
            is acquired by the capture devices belongs to the sample that is used for PAD. Note:
            Compliance to this security objective can be easily shown by providing a certificate for
            the biometric system in the environment showing that the biometric system fulfils all
            the requirements from [bioCPP]. </description>
          <appnote>The PAD system addressed in this Protection Profile is a protection mechanism
            against presentation attacks.</appnote>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.PAD" toe-type="BIO">
          <description>The biometric system shall be protected against Presentation Attacks
            according to PP [padCPP]. Note: Compliance to this security objective can be shown by
            providing a Common Criteria certificate for the PAD system in the environment showing
            that the PAD system fulfils all the requirements from [padCPP]. </description>
          <appnote>The biometric system addressed in this Protection Profile serves to authenticate
            users and does not provide any functionality for PAD.</appnote>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.PAD" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The environment shall provide functionality to associate users with roles.
            This functionality of the environment is an important aspect that contributes to counter
            threats that include aspects of a role model (like T.Roles). The minimum TOE as defined
            in this Protection Profile may not have the functionality to distinguish roles for
            users. For that reason, this functionality is provided by the environment.
          </description>
        </SOE>
        <SOE id="OE.AdminAuth" toe-type="BIO PAD INT">
          <description>The environment shall provide a secure and non biometric authentication
            mechanism for the authentication of administrators. </description>
        </SOE>
      </SOEs>
    </section>
    <section id="SOR" title="Security Objectives Rationale">This section describes how the
      assumptions, threats, and organizational security policies map to the security objectives.
      
      
      <InsertSPDCorrespondence/></section>
  </chapter>
  <!-- ********************************************
                               _ _      
   _. _ _ _   _ __   ___ _ __   __| (_)_  __
  / _` | '_ \| '_ \ / _ \ '_ \ / _` | \ \/ /
 | (_| | |_) | |_) |  __/ | | | (_| | |>< 
  \__,_| .__/| .__/ \___|_| |_|\__,_|_/_/\_\
       |_|   |_|            
********************************************
 -->
  <appendix id="biblio" title="References">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="CC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - 
          
          
          <htm:ul>
            <htm:li>
              <htm:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                1: Introduction and General Model</htm:a>
              , CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision
              4, September 2012.</htm:li>
            <htm:li>
              <htm:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                2: Security Functional Components</htm:a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</htm:li>
            <htm:li>
              <htm:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                3: Security Assurance Components</htm:a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</htm:li>
          </htm:ul>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="CEM">
        <tag>CEM</tag>
        <description>
          <htm:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CEMV3.1R4.pdf">Common
            Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security - Evaluation
            Methodology</htm:a>, CCMB-2012-09-004, Version 3.1, Revision 4, September
          2012.</description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>
  <appendix id="ack" title="Acknowledgements">Tbd</appendix>
  <extra-css>
    <!--  .LsVerySpecificUseCase::before { content: "Note["; }
  .LsVerySpecificUseCase { text-decoration: line-through;}
  .LsVerySpecificUseCase::after { content: "]"; }-->
    <!-- <htm:div class="LsVerySpecificUseCase">-->.SOlist .optional::after, .SOlist
    .sel-based::after, .SOlist .objective::after { content: &quot;(OPTIONAL)&quot; } </extra-css>
</PP>